we are to prove Pythagoras Theorem c² =
a sare +
b² that is hypot square is equal to sum
of squares of other two
sides we will prove it by the Yan
property this property says that square
a
square will be changed to rectangle
whose area will be a square and square
with area b square will be changed to
rectangle whose area will be b s
now see the animation
process first
slider ch ches scares to
parallelogram and these have area same
because we have applied rule on the
right hand side given area and
parallelogram area of the both sides
figures are same because they have the
same base and same
height now see animation
these have three steps so off slider one
off slider two offsider
three you can repeat it first second
third third second 1 1 2
3 C animation again
step third second
one step first second
third third second 1 1 step two step
three therefore a square + b square
are merged in the big Square
c² therefore c² = to a sare + b square
Please Subscribe and share my channel